DOMINIC LACAILLE

Montreal, Canada

▶ phone +1 (514) 984 0393

in linkedin linkedin.com/in/dominic-lacaille-mtl

summary

Developer with 11 years experience who has designed and developed over 30 web, mobile, and server applications from use cases and functional requirements. His great ease researching and solving complex problems brings a marked advantage in research and development.

work experience

2020–Present Senior Front-End Dev., Vanilla Forums — Montreal

Vanilla Forums

- Creates an analytics interface in React Typescript with live data
- Develops dynamic customizations to the look and feel of the forum
- Develops a declarative solution for generating complex forms
- Maintains and improves the core of Vanilla Forums and it's plugins in both PHP and React Typescript

2015–2020 Application Software Dev., Voxco — Montreal

Voxco Canada

- · Develops an offline survey engine in React
- Develops a Single Sign-On (SSO) authentication system
- Develops and designs an offline personal interview application (CAPI) for Android and iOS with over 2,000 monthly active users
- Participates in an Agile team with a fast release cycle
- Develops various APIs to support mobile applications

2012–2015 Full Stack Dev., Appcom — Longueuil

Appcom

- Develops and designs applications for quads, snowmobiles and leisure boats with more than 100,000 downloads on Google Play and Apple App Store, combining cartography technologies and point-of-interest management APIs
- Develops sales websites for points-of-interest
- Develops and integrates WordPress websites, plugins and themes for WordPress in PHP
- Maintains ArcGIS cartography servers
- Develops software for precisely triangulating a device's position using Bluetooth beacons
- Creates tools to manipulate geographical data and generate tiled maps

education

2010–2013 Édouard-Montpetit College — Longueuil

College Diploma Computer Science · Specialization: Business Computing

2013 Java Dev. Intern, McKesson — Montreal

McKesson Canada

Maintains and develops Java web applications for Liferay and PostgreSQL used daily by pharmacists and doctors

personal projects

2019 Findjoo Mobile for Android/iOS

Findjoo Mobile

Cross-platform React Native application. Provides members and event organizers with an easy to use interface to manage their calendar, scan tickets and receive important notifications.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.findjoomobile

2016 Jayson Serializer/Deserializer

Jayson Objective-C JSON Library with the aim to provide simple serialization and deserialization for complex types, arrays and value types.

https://github.com/ldom66/jayson

skills

Programming Javascript, TypeScript, Java, Python, C#, PHP 7, Objective-C, C++, LTEX, Kotlin, Swift,

Languages EBNF, Regex, SQL

Development VS Code, Visual Studio, Android Studio, Xcode, Sublime Text, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Atom

Environments

Mobile React Native, iOS, Android

Web React, Redux, REST, Apollo GraphQL, .NET Core, Node.js, Webpack

Testing Mocha, Jest, JUnit, TDD

Project Jira, ZenHub

Management

Databases Realm, SQL Server, Entity Framework, MySQL, PostgreSQL

other information

Languages Français · Langue maternelle

English · Bilingual

Interests Programming · Photography · Music

References upon request

October 22, 2021